Author	Year	PMID	Study type	Paper name	
Yamazaki	2012	22840716	retrospective cohort	Increased incidence of osteonecrosis of the jaw after tooth extraction in patients treated with bisphosphonates: a cohort study	
Chiu	2014	24758181	retrospective cohort	The Risk of Osteonecrosis of the Jaws in Taiwanese Osteoporotic Patients Treated With Oral Alendronate or Raloxifene	
Baillargeon	2011	21954448	"retrospective cohort, 
matched-subject"	Osteonecrosis of the Jaw in Older Osteoporosis Patients Treated with Intravenous Bisphosphonates	
Eiken	2017	28664276	retrospective cohort	"Surgically treated osteonecrosis and osteomyelitis of the jaw and oral cavity in patients highly adherent to alendronate treatment: a nationwide user-only cohort study including over 60,000 alendronate users"	
Fujimori	2025		"retrospective cohort, 
multi-centered"	A multicenter retrospective study of the risk factors associated with medication-related osteonecrosis of the jaw after tooth extraction in patients receiving oral bisphosphonate therapy: can primary wound closure and a drug holiday really prevent MRONJ?	
Kang	2020	32158685	retrospective cohort	The effect of bisphosphonate discontinuation on the incidence  of postoperative medication-related osteonecrosis of the jaw after tooth extraction	
Grbic*	2010	21037195	"RCT, 
multi-centered"	The Incidence of Osteonecrosis of the Jaw in Patients Receiving 5 Milligrams of Zoledronic Acid	
Orwoll	2010	20499357	RCT	"Efficacy and safety of a once-yearly i.v. Infusion of zoledronic acid 5 mg versus a once-weekly 70-mg oral alendronate in the treatment of male osteoporosis: a randomized, multicenter, double-blind, active-controlled study"	
McClung	2009	20168099	RCT	Zoledronic acid for the prevention of bone loss in postmenopausal women with low bone mass: a randomized controlled trial	
Reid	2009	19362675	RCT	"Zoledronic acid and risedronate in the prevention and treatment of glucocorticoid-induced osteoporosis (HORIZON): a multicentre, double-blind, double-dummy, randomised controlled trial"	
Lyles	2007	17878149	RCT	Zoledronic acid and clinical fractures and mortality after hip fracture	
Grbic	2008	18167382	RCT	Incidence of osteonecrosis of the jaw in women with postmenopausal osteoporosis in the health outcomes and reduced incidence with zoledronic acid once yearly pivotal fracture trial	
Kim	2021	32956854	retrospective cohort	Incidence of and risk for osteonecrosis of the jaw in Korean osteoporosis patients treated with bisphosphonates: A nationwide cohort-study	
Jeong	2017	28361029	retrospective cohort	Risk factors of osteonecrosis of the jaw after tooth extraction in osteoporotic patients on oral bisphosphonates	
Mirelli	2022	35621542	retrospective cohort	Medication-Related Osteonecrosis of the Jaw in Dental Practice: A Retrospective Analysis of Data from the Milan Cohort	
Mahvar	2023		"retrospective cohort, 
matched-subject"	10-Year Institutional Retrospective Case-Control Study of Medication-Related Osteonecrosis of the Jaw	
Papapoulos	2012	22113951	RCT	Five years of denosumab exposure in women with postmenopausal osteoporosis: Results from the first two years of the FREEDOM extension	
Everts-Graber 	2022	34787342	retrospective cohort	Risk of Osteonecrosis of the Jaw Under Denosumab Compared to Bisphosphonates in Patients With Osteoporosis	
Watts	2019	30759221	RCT	Invasive Oral Procedures and Events in Postmenopausal Women With Osteoporosis Treated With Denosumab for Up to 10 Years	
Wei	2025	39611589	retrospective cohort	Risk Factors Influencing Medication-Related Osteonecrosis of the Jaws (MRONJ) Following Dental Extraction Among Osteoporotic Patients in Taiwan	
Colella	2023	36442534	retrospective cohort	What is the Risk of Developing Osteonecrosis Following Dental Extractions for Patients on Denosumab for Osteoporosis?	
Saag	2017	28892457	RCT	Romosozumab or Alendronate for Fracture Prevention in Women with Osteoporosis	
					
					
Coleman-2020	2020	31806543	RCT	"Adjuvant denosumab in early breast cancer (D-CARE): an international, multicentre, randomised, controlled, phase 3 trial"	
O'Carrigan	2017	29082518	Systematic review	Bisphosphonates and other bone agents for breast cancer	
Macherey	2017	29278410	Systematic review	Bisphosphonates for advanced prostate cancer	
Gnant 	2015	25403582	RCT	Zoledronic acid combined with adjuvant endocrine therapy of tamoxifen versus anastrozol plus ovarian function suppression in premenopausal early breast cancer: final analysis of the Austrian Breast and Colorectal Cancer Study Group Trial 12	
Coleman-2014	2014	25035292	RCT	Adjuvant zoledronic acid in patients with early breast cancer: final efficacy analysis of the AZURE (BIG 01/04) randomised open-label phase 3 trial	
Valachis	2013	23404816	Systematic review	Adjuvant therapy with zoledronic acid in patients with breast cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis	
Boquete-Castro	2016	25639776	Systematic review	Denosumab and osteonecrosis of the jaw. A systematic analysis of events reported in clinical trials	
Raje	2018	29429912	RCT	"Denosumab versus zoledronic acid in bone disease treatment of newly diagnosed multiple myeloma: an international, double-blind, double-dummy, randomised, controlled, phase 3 study"	
Himelstein	2017	28030702	RCT	Effect of Longer-Interval vs Standard Dosing of Zoledronic Acid on Skeletal Events in Patients With Bone Metastases: A Randomized Clinical Trial	
Henry	2014	24162260	RCT	Delaying skeletal-related events in a randomized phase 3 study of denosumab versus zoledronic acid in patients with advanced cancer: an analysis of data from patients with solid tumors	
Peddi	2013	22898302	Systematic review	Denosumab in patients with cancer and skeletal metastases: a systematic review and meta-analysis	
Wang	2014	24932278	Systematic review	Comparison of the efficacy and safety of denosumab versus bisphosphonates in breast cancer and bone metastases treatment: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials	
Ng	2021	32535678	Systematic review	Long-term impact of bone-modifying agents for the treatment of bone metastases: a systematic review	
Yang	2019	31217825	Systematic review	The incidence and relative risk of adverse events in patients treated with bisphosphonate therapy for breast cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis	
